Register of the Pathfinder Press Publications, 1922-2014
Hoover Institution Archives
- MONAD PRESS IMPRINTS, 1972-1986. (Box 23-26)
  Books published by Monad Press. All items published in New York City. Arranged chronologically.
  - Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trials. Not Guilty: Report of the Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trials. 2nd edition. 422 p., 1972. (Box 23)
  - Dobbs, Farrell. Teamster Rebellion. 195 p. Cf. Related Foreign (France, Japan) imprints, 1972.
  - Mandel, Ernest. Decline of the Dollar: A Marxist View of the Monetary Crisis. 128 p., 1972. (Box 24)
  - Trotsky, Leon. The First Five Years of the Communist International. 2nd edition. 1972. 2 volumes. First published by Pioneer Publishers q.v.), (1945-1953
  - Dobbs, Farrell. Teamster Power. 255 p., 1973.
  - Herreshoff, David. The Origins of American Marxism: From the Transcendentalists to DeLeon. 215 p., 1973.
  - Kutcher, James. The Case of the Legless Veteran. 255 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Great Britain) imprint, 1973.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Leon Trotsky on Britain. 334 p., 1973.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Problems of Everyday Life: And Other Writings on Culture and Science. 352 p., 1973.
  - Dziuba, Ivan. Internationalism or Russification? A Study in the Soviet Nationalities Problem. By Ivan Dzyuba. 262 p., 1974.
  - Kofsky, Frank. Lenny Bruce: The Comedian as Social Critic and Secular Moralist. 128 p., 1974.
  - Samizdat: Voices of the Soviet Opposition. Edited by George Saunders [pseudonym of George Shriver] 464 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Japan) imprint, 1974.
  - Dobbs, Farrell. Teamster Politics. 256 p., 1975.
  - Camejo, Peter. Racism, Revolution, Reaction, 1861-1877: The Rise and Fall of Radical Reconstruction. 269 p., 1976.
  - Medvedev, Roy. Detente and Socialist Democracy: A Discussion with Roy Medvedev. By Yvan Craipeau et al.; edited by Ken Coates. 163 p., 1976.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Istoriia Russkoi Revoliutsii [The History of the Russian Revolution. Russian version] Facsimile edition. 3 volumes in 1. Cf. Pathfinder (1980) imprint, 1976. (Box 25)
  - Trotsky, Leon. Leon Trotsky on China. Edited by Les Evans and Russell Block. 687 p., 1976.
  - The Autobiographies of the Haymarket Martyrs. Edited by Philip S. Foner. 198 p., 1977.
  - Dobbs, Farrell. Teamster Bureaucracy. 304 p., 1977.
  - Evans, Les. China after Mao. 191 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Hong Kong) imprint, 1978.
  - Halstead, Fred. Out Now! A Participant's Account of the American Movement against the Vietnam War. 759 p. Cf. Pathfinder (1991) imprint, 1978.
  - Novack, George. Polemics in Marxist Philosophy. 344 p., 1978.
  - Lenin, V. I. Kronstadt. By V. I. Lenin and Leon Trotsky. 159 p., 1979.
  - Siegel, Paul N. Revolution and the Twentieth-Century Novel. 237 p., 1979.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Leon Trotsky on France. 271 p., 1979.
  - Dobbs, Farrell. Revolutionary Continuity: Marxist Leadership in the U.S.: The Early Years, 1848-1917. 221 p., 1980.
  - Peng, Shu-tse. The Chinese Communist Party in Power. 508 p., 1980.
  - Cannon, James P. The Left Opposition in the U.S., 1928-31: Writings and Speeches. 446 p., 1981. (Box 26)
  - Socialist Workers Party. The Founding of the Socialist Workers Party: Minutes and Resolutions, 1938-39. 395 p., 1982.
  - Dobbs, Farrell. Revolutionary Continuity: Marxist Leadership in the U.S.: Birth of the Communist Movement, 1918-1922. 240 p., 1983.
  - Harsch, Ernest. South Africa: White Rule, Black Revolt. 2nd edition. 352 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Sweden) imprint, 1983.
  - Jones, Mother. Mother Jones Speaks: Collected Speeches and Writings. Edited by Philip S. Foner. 724 p., 1983.
  - Lenin's Struggle for a Revolutionary International: Documents, 1907-1916: The Preparatory Years. Edited by John Riddell. 604 p., 1984.
  - ----------. 2nd edition. 604 p. Cf. Education for Socialists (1984) imprint, 1986.
  - Cannon, James P. The Communist League of America, 1932-34: Writings and Speeches. 439 p., 1985.
- EDUCATION FOR SOCIALISTS BULLETINS, 1968-1992. (Box 27-28)
  Series of bulletins begun under the imprint of the Socialist Workers Party National Education Department and continued by Pathfinder Press. All items published in New York City. Arranged chronologically.
  - Defense Policies and Principles of the Socialist Workers Party. 20 p., 1968. (Box 27)
  - Studies in Afro-American History. 35 p., 1968.
  - Class, Party, and State and the Eastern European Revolution. 61 p., 1969.
  - The Development and Disintegration of World Stalinism. 77 p., 1970.
  - Socialist Workers Party. The Organizational Character of the Socialist Workers Party. 24 p., 1970.
  - Aspects of Socialist Election Policy. 88 p., 1971.
  - Dobbs, Farrell. The Structure and Organizational Principles of the Party. 37 p., 1971.
  - Hansen, Joseph. The Abern Clique. 32 p., 1972.
  - Peng, Shu-tse. The Chinese Revolution. By Peng Shu-tse and Peng Pi-lan [Ch'en Pi-lan] Parts II-III, 1972.
  - Selected Documents on SWP Trade Union Policy. 21 p., 1972.
  - Horowitz, Gus. Israel and the Arab Revolution: Fundamental Principles of Revolutionary Marxism. 64 p., 1973.
  - Against Violence within the Workers Movement. 32 p., 1974.
  - Hansen, Joseph. The Workers and Farmers Government. 65 p., 1974.
  - James P. Cannon: A Political Tribute. 46 p., 1974.
  - Marxism vs. Ultraleftism: The Record of Healy's Break with Trotskyism. Edited by Joseph Hansen. 253 p., 1974.
  - Cannon, James P. The Revolutionary Perspective for the United States. 37 p., 1975.
  - From Mississippi to Boston: The Demand for Troops to Enforce Civil Rights. 32 p., 1975.
  - Revolutionary Strategy in the Fight against the Vietnam War. 94 p., 1975.
  - Towards a History of the Fourth International. volumes in 1, 1975? 12
  - Cannon, James P. What Is American Fascism? Writings on Father Coughlin, Mayor Frank Hague, and Senator Joseph McCarthy. By James P. Cannon and Joseph Hansen. 47 p., 1976.
  - The Chinese Revolution and Its Development. 47 p., 1976.
  - Dobbs, Farrell. Counter-mobilization: A Strategy to Fight Racist and Fascist Attacks. 23 p., 1976.
  - The Fight against Fascism in the USA: Forty Years of Struggle Described by Participants. By James P. Cannon et al. p., 1976? 53
  - Healy's Big Lie: The Slander Campaign against Joseph Hansen, George Novack, and the Fourth International. By Joseph Hansen et al. 87 p., 1976.
  - Kerry, Tom. Class Struggle Policy in the Rise of the Labor Movement. 22 p., 1976.
  - Pearlman, Bob. Spartacist League: The Making of an American Sect. 16 p., 1977.
  - The Struggle to Reunify the Fourth International, 1954-1963. 4 volumes, 1977-1978. (Box 28)
  - Chester, Bob. Workers and Farmers Governments since the Second World War. 39 p., 1978.
  - Horowitz, Gus. Revolutionists and the Fight against Imperialist Intervention in Angola: A Reply to Nahuel Moreno. 13 p., 1978.
  - Kerry, Tom. Anatomia del estalinismo. 14 p., 1978.
  - Background to The Struggle for a Proletarian Party. By James P. Cannon et al. 45 p. Cf. Pathfinder (1972) imprint, 1979.
  - Breitman, George. The Rocky Road to the Fourth International, 1933-38. 21 p., 1979.
  - Castro, Fidel. Selected Speeches. Bound with Jack Barnes, Twenty Years of the Cuban Revolution. 134 p., 1979.
  - ----------. Reprint. 134 p., 1992.
  - Marxism and the Working Farmer. 62 p., 1979.
  - Barnes, Jack. The Nicaraguan Workers' and Farmers' Government and the Revolutionary Leadership of the FSLN. 46 p., 1980.
  - Clark, Steve. Grenada: A Workers' and Farmers' Government with a Revolutionary Proletarian Leadership. 36 p., 1980.
  - Hansen, Joseph. James P. Cannon the Internationalist. 38 p., 1980.
  - Revolutionary Cuba Today: The Record of a Discussion. 136 p., 1980.
  - Waters, Mary-Alice. Proletarian Leadership in Power: What We Can Learn from Lenin, Castro, and the FSLN. 39 p., 1980.
  - Bailey, Nan. The National Black Independent Political Party. By Nan Bailey, Malik Miah and Mac Warren. 32 p., 1981.
  - Castro, Fidel. Fidel Castro on Chile. 158 p., 1982.
  - Independent Black Political Action, 1954-78. Edited by Mac Warren. 72 p., 1982.
  - Dobbs, Farrell. Selected Articles on the Labor Movement. 31 p. Cf. Related U.S. (1967) imprint, 1983.
  - Study Guide to Lenin's Struggle for a Revolutionary International. 23 p. Cf. Monad (1984) imprint
  - Barnes, Jack. For a Workers' and Farmers' Government in the United States. 61 p., 1985.
  - Jenness, Doug. Bolshevism and the Russian Revolution: A Debate. By Doug Jenness and Ernest Mandel. 68 p., 1985.
  - The Split of the Australian Socialist Workers Party National Committee from the Fourth International. 68 p., 1985.
  - Two Study Guides on Lenin's Writings. 19 p., 1988.
  - Socialist Workers Party. Communist Continuity and the Fight for Women's Liberation: Documents of the Socialist Workers Party, 1971-86. 3 volumes, 1992.
- RELATED UNITED STATES IMPRINTS, 1922-1994 (Box 29-31)
  Publications distributed by Pathfinder Press, including books and pamphlets issued under the imprint of the Socialist Workers Party, its predecessors and affiliates, and associated election campaign and legal defense organizations; and translations of Pathfinder Press publications. Arranged chronologically.
  - Cannon, James P. The Fifth Year of the Russian Revolution: A Report of a Lecture. New York: Workers Party of America, 21 p., 1922. (Box 29)
  - Trotsky, Leon. The Draft Program of the Communist International: A Criticism of Fundamentals. New York: The Militant, 139 p., 1929.
  - Trotsky, Leon. The Strategy of the World Revolution. New York: Communist League of America (Opposition), 86 p., 1930.
  - Trotsky, Leon. The Turn in the Communist International and the German Situation. New York: Communist League of America (Opposition), 32 p., 1930.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Communism and Syndicalism: On the Trade Union Question. New York: Communist League of America (Opposition), 63 p., 1931.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Problems of the Development of the U.S.S.R.: Draft of the Thesis of the International Left Opposition on the Russian Question. New York: Communist League of America (Opposition), 48 p., 1931.
  - Trotsky, Leon. The Revolution in Spain. New York: Communist League of America (Opposition), 32 p., 1931.
  - Trotsky, Leon. World Unemployment and the Five Year Plan. New York: Communist League of America (Opposition), 22 p., 1931.
  - Oehler, Hugo. America's Role in Germany. Philadelphia: Communist League of America (Opposition), 18 p., 1933.
  - Weisbord, Albert. For a New Communist International! New York: Communist League of Struggle, 30 p., 1933.
  - United Workers Party of America. Bolshevism or Communism: On the Question of a New Communist Party and the "Fourth" International. United Workers Party of America, 15 p., 1934.
  - Burnham, James. War and the Workers. By John West [pseudonym] Workers Party of U.S., 47 p., 1935.
  - Goldman, Albert. From Communism to Socialism. 14 p., 1935.
  - Marlen, George. Paris on the Barricades. New York: Spartacus Youth League of America, 60 p., 1935.
  - Solow, Herbert. Union-Smashing in Sacramento: The Truth about the Criminal Syndicalism Trial. New York: National Sacramento Appeal Committee, 31 p., 1935.
  - Tyler, Gus. Youth Fights War! Chicago: Young People's Socialist League, p., 1935? 23
  - Zeller, Fred. The Road for Revolutionary Socialists. New York: New Militant Publishing Company, 29 p., 1935.
  - Out of Their Own Mouths: A Documentary Study of the New Line of the Comintern on War. Edited by Harold Draper. New York: Young People's Socialist League, p., 1936? 39
  - Breitman, George. The Workers Alliance vs. Mr. Mudd and the F.A.C. Trenton: Workers Alliance of New Jersey, 16 p., 1937.
  - Draper, Hal. Are You Ready for War? Young People's Socialist League, p., 1937? 18
  - What Is the Non-Partisan Labor Defense? Non-Partisan Labor Defense, p., 1937? 15
  - Breitman, George. The Fight against Hagueism: A Program of Action. Socialist Workers Party, 16 p., 1938.
  - Burnham, James. How to Fight War? Socialist Workers Party and Young People's Socialist League (Fourth Internationalist), 15 p., 1938.
  - Preis, Art. America's Permanent Depression: The Truth about Unemployment. New York: Socialist Workers Party, 19 p., 1938.
  - Socialist Workers Party. Declaration of Principles and Constitution of the Socialist Workers Party. New York: Socialist Workers Party, 31 p., 1938.
  - Socialist Workers Party. Minnesota Section. The Farmer-Labor Party: A Program: An Open Letter to Governor Benson. New York: Socialist Workers Party, 15 p., 1938.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Leon Sedoff: Son, Friend, Fighter. New York: Young People's Socialist League (Fourth Internationalist), 31 p., 1938.
  - We, the Youth. Chicago: Young People's Socialist League (Fourth Internationalist), p., 1938? 12
  - Wright, John G. The Truth about Kronstadt. New York: Socialist Workers Party National Educational Department, p., 1938? 17
  - Fourth International. The Founding Conference of the Fourth International, World Party of the Socialist Revolution: Program and Resolutions. New York: Socialist Workers Party, 127 p., 1939.
  - Gould, Nathan. Youth Want Jobs. Young People's Socialist League (Fourth Internationalist), p., 1939? 10
  - Behind the 544 Suit. Minneapolis: Northwest Organizer, 38 p., 1940.
  - Breitman, George. Vote against Jim Crow! By Albert Parker [pseudonym] Socialist Workers Party, 13 p., 1940.
  - Fourth International. Manifesto of the Fourth International on the Imperialist War and the Proletarian Revolution. New York: Socialist Workers Party, 46 p., 1940.
  - Macdonald, Dwight. Jobs, Not Battleships! New York: Socialist Workers Party, 16 p., 1940.
  - New Jersey in the 1940 Elections. Socialist Workers Party, 13 p.
  - Macdonald, Dwight. The War's Greatest Scandal! The Story of Jim Crow in Uniform. New York: March on Washington Movement, 15 p., 1941.
  - Novack, George. The Bill of Rights in Danger! The Meaning of the Minneapolis Convictions. New York: Civil Rights Defense Committee, 15 p., 1941.
  - Novack, George. Witch Hunt in Minnesota: The Federal Prosecution of the Socialist Workers Party and Local 544-C.I.O. New York: Civil Rights Defense Committee, 23 p., 1941.
  - Novack, George. An Introduction to the Logic of Marxism: Eight Lectures. By William F. Warde [pseudonym] New York: Socialist Workers Party Educational Department, 83 p. Subsequent editions published by Pioneer Publishers (1963, q.v.), Merit Publishers (1966, q.v.) and Pathfinder Press (1971, q.v.) Cf. Related Foreign (Argentina, Greece, Mexico, Spain) imprints, 1942.
  - Thomas, C. West Coast Longshoremen and the "Bridges" Plan. 25 p., 1943.
  - Who Are the Eighteen Prisoners in the Minneapolis Labor Case? New York: Civil Rights Defense Committee, 27 p., 1944.
  - Weiss, Myra Tanner. Vigilante Terror in Fontana: The Tragic Story of O'Day H. Short and His Family. Los Angeles: Socialist Workers Party, 20 p., 1946.
  - Socialist Workers Party. For a Workers and Farmers Government: 1948 Election Platform. New York: Socialist Workers Party, 13 p.
  - Socialist Workers Party. 1952 Election Platform. New York: Socialist Workers Party, 13 p.
  - Socialist Workers Party. Vote for Socialism in 1956. New York: Socialist Workers Party, 16 p.
  - Haessler, Carl. Should Progressives Work in the Democratic Party? A Debate. By Carl Haessler and George Breitman. Detroit: Friday Night Socialist Forum, 32 p., 1959.
  - Lovell, Frank. How Democratic Is the United States? Detroit: Forum Pamphlets, 10 p., 1960.
  - Castro, Fidel. Castro Speaks on Unemployment. New York: Young Socialist Forum, 24 p., 1961. (Box 30)
  - Index, 1934-1960 [to New International, Fourth International and International Socialist Review] New York: International Socialist Review Publishing Association, 60 p., 1961.
  - Nelson, Truman. People with Strength in Monroe, North Carolina. New York: Committee to Aid the Monroe Defendants, 37 p., 1961.
  - Young Socialist Alliance. Introducing the Y.S.A. New York: Young Socialist Forum, 6 p., 1961.
  - McRae, Leroy. The Indiana "Subversion" Speech. New York: Committee to Aid the Bloomington Students, 26 p., 1963.
  - Breitman, George. How a Minority Can Change Society. New York: Young Socialist Forum, 27 p. Subsequent editions published by Merit Publishers (1966, q.v.) and Pathfinder Press (1971, q.v.), 1964.
  - Socialist Workers Party. Socialist Workers Party Election Platform. New York: Socialist Workers Party, 11 p., 1964.
  - Jenness, Doug. War and Revolution in Vietnam. New York: Young Socialist, 22 p., 1965.
  - ----------. 3rd edition. Young Socialist Alliance, 22 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Greece) imprint, 1970.
  - Jenness, Doug. The War in Vietnam. By Doug Jenness and Robin Martin. New York: Young Socialist, 15 p., 1965.
  - Roberts, Dick. Revolution in the Congo. New York: Young Socialist, 22 p., 1965.
  - X, Malcolm. Malcolm X Talks to Young People. New York: Young Socialist, 36 p., 1965.
  - ----------. 2nd printing. 36 p. Subsequent edition published by Pathfinder Press (1969, q.v.) Cf. Pathfinder (1991) imprint, 1966.
  - The Fort Hood Three: The Case of the Three G.I.'s Who Said "No" to the War in Vietnam. New York: Fort Hood Three Defense Committee, 31 p., 1966.
  - Healy "Reconstructs" the Fourth International: Documents and Comments by Participants in a Fiasco. New York: Socialist Workers Party, 40 p., 1966.
  - Jenness, Caroline. Immediate Withdrawal vs. Negotiations: Questions and Answers on Which Way for the Antiwar Movement. Cambridge, Mass.: Bring the Troops Home Now Newsletter, 14 p., 1966.
  - X, Malcolm. Malcolm X Speaks: Selected Speeches and Statements. Edited by George Breitman. New York: Grove Press, 226 p. First published by Merit Publishers (1965, q.v.), 1966.
  - ----------. Reprint. Grove Weidenfeld, 1990. 226 p. Cf. Pathfinder imprints, (1984, 1989, 1993)
  - Dobbs, Farrell. Recent Trends in the Labor Movement. New York: Socialist Workers Party National Education Department, p. Subsequent edition published as Education for Socialists bulletin (1983, q.v.), 1967? 31
  - Free Speech for GIs: The Case of Pfc. Howard Petrick, a Soldier Opposed to the Vietnam War. New York: Committee to Defend the Rights of Pfc. Howard Petrick, 23 p., 1967.
  - Land or Death: Hugo Blanco and the Peasant Struggle in Peru. New York: Young Socialist Alliance, 22 p. Cf. Pathfinder (1972) imprint, 1967.
  - Waters, Mary-Alice. G.I.'s and the Fight against War. New York: Young Socialist, 31 p., 1967.
  - Zionism and the Arab Revolution: The Myth of Progressive Israel. New York: Young Socialist Alliance, 31 p., 1967.
  - ----------. 3rd printing. 31 p., 1969.
  - Cannon, James P. Socialist Election Policy in 1958. Minneapolis: Socialist Workers Party, 11 p. Reprint of Pioneer Publishers edition (1958, q.v.), 1968.
  - France: The Struggle Continues. New York: Committee to Defend the French Students, 31 p., 1968.
  - Mandel, Ernest. An Introduction to Marxist Economic Theory. New York: Young Socialist, 78 p., 1968.
  - ----------. 3rd printing. 78 p. Subsequent edition published by Pathfinder Press (1973, q.v.), 1969.
  - Revolt in France, May-June 1968: A Contemporary Record. New York: Les Evans, 168 p.
  - Socialist Workers Party. The Case for a Black Party. New York: Socialist Workers Party, 22 p. Cf. Pathfinder (1971) imprint, 1968.
  - Fourth International. The Worldwide Youth Radicalization and the Tasks of the Fourth International. New York: Young Socialist Alliance, 29 p., 1969.
  - Mandel, Ernest. On Workers Democracy. New York: Young Socialist Alliance, 4 p., 1969.
  - Mandel, Ernest. The Revolutionary Student Movement: Theory and Practice. New York: Young Socialist Alliance, 39 p. Subsequent edition published by Pathfinder Press (1971, q.v.), 1969.
  - Waters, Mary-Alice. Maoism in the U.S.: A Critical History of the Progressive Labor Party. New York: Young Socialist Alliance, 23 p. Cf. Related Foreign (Italy) imprint, 1969.
  - Reed, Evelyn. Aya sarnivisht-i zan ra sakhtiman-i badani-u ta'yin mikunad? [Is Biology Woman's Destiny? Persian translation] Los Angeles: Intisharat-i Zaman, 31 p. Cf. Pathfinder (1972) imprint, ca. 1970s.
  - Singer, Stu. The Real Ted Kennedy: Crusading Reformer for the Poor, or Calculating Politician for the Rich? Boston: Socialist Workers Party Campaign Committee, 16 p., 1970.
  - Reed, Evelyn. Dar barah-'i situm kashidagi-i zan dar Iran: Bi-inzimam-i Tarjumah-'i maqalah-'i Zan va khvanvadah, yak bar'rasi-i Tarikhi [Problems of Women's Liberation. Persian translation] New York: Intishirat-i Fanus, 63 p. Cf. Merit (1969) and Pathfinder (1970) imprints, 1972.
  - In Defense of Mustafa Dzhemilev. By Reza Baraheni et al. New York: Mustafa Dzhemilev Defense Committee, 22 p., 1976.
  - Marx, Karl. Bayaniyah-'i kumunist [The Communist Manifesto. Persian translation] By Karl Marks and Firidrik Ingils [Engels] New York: Intisharat-i Fanus, 78 p. Cf. Pathfinder (1970) imprint, 1976.
  - Bar'rasi-i susyalisti. New York: Barresi Sosialisti. No. 1., 1978
  - Dinamism-i kanuni-i inqilab-i jahani [Dynamics of World Revolution Today. Persian translation] New York: Intisharat-i Fanus, 219 p. Cf. Pathfinder (1974) imprint, 1978.
  - Marroquin, Hector. My Story: The Struggle for Political Asylum in the U.S. New York: Hector Marroquin Defense Committee, 15 p., 1978.
  - Marroquin, Hector. Mi historia: La lucha por el asilo politico en los Estados Unidos [My Story. Spanish version] New York: Hector Marroquin Defense Committee, 22 p., 1978.
  - Trotsky, Leon. Linin-i javan [The Young Lenin. Persian translation] New York: Intisharat-i Fanus, 318 p., 1978.
  - Pulley, Andrew. How I Became a Socialist. New York: Socialist Workers Presidential Campaign Committee, 45 p., 1980.
  - ----------. Reprint. Young Socialist, 45 p., 1981.
  - Pulley, Andrew. Por que soy socialista [How I Became a Socialist. Spanish translation] New York: Socialist Workers Presidential Campaign Committee, 44 p., 1980.
  - Pulley, Andrew. Why Working People Need a Labor Party. New York: Socialist Workers Presidential Campaign Committee, 46 p., 1980.
  - New International: A Magazine of Marxist Politics and Theory. New York: 408 Printing and Publishing Corporation. No. 1983-1994. Includes first and second printings of No. 2 (Box 31)
  - Nouvelle internationale: Une revue de theorie et de politique marxistes. New York: 408 Printing and Publishing Corporation. No. 1985-1991, 1-4.
  - Nueva internacional: Una revista de politica y teoria marxistas. New York: 408 Printing and Publishing Corporation. No. 1991, 1-2.
- RELATED FOREIGN IMPRINTS, 1937-1993 (Box 32-39)
  Publications distributed by Pathfinder Press, including translations of books and pamphlets published by Pathfinder Press and its predecessors. Arranged alphabetically by country of publication.
  - Argentina (Box 32)
    - Trotsky, Leon. La liberacion de la mujer. By Leon Trotsky, Caroline Lund and Elizabeth Barnes [Stone] Ediciones Eleve, 50 p., ca. 1970s.
    - Buch, Peter. La crisis de Medio Oriente [Burning Issues of the Mideast Crisis. Spanish translation] Buenos Aires: Ediciones Eleve, 28 p. Cf. Merit (1969) imprint, 1971.
    - Moreno, Nahuel. Feudalismo y capitalismo en la colonizacion de America: Una respuesta a Andre Gunder Frank. By Nahuel Moreno and George Novack. Buenos Aires: Ediciones Avanzada, 20 p., 1972.
    - Novack, George. Introduccion a la logica marxista [An Introduction to the Logic of Marxism. Spanish translation] Buenos Aires: Ediciones Pluma, 126 p. Cf. Related U.S. (1942), Pioneer (1963), Merit (1966) and Pathfinder (1971) imprints, 1973.
    - Trotsky, Leon. El programa de transicion para la revolucion socialista [The Transitional Program for Socialist Revolution. Spanish translation] Buenos Aires: Ediciones Pluma, 115 p. Cf. Pathfinder (1973) imprint